I would call it over the Reggers Academy in the Madison City Council for June 3rd, 2024.
Number two, public hearing on the proposed fiscal year 24, 25 budget.
It's all a good.
Hi.
First off, I want to say welcome to private Jones.
You are my new counsel.
I'm in your district, your ward.
My name is Kit Waters.
I am here to speak on behalf of the library.
I am on the board of directors for the library.
And I just want to start off with children who do not read in the summer can
lose two to three months of reading skills.
And kids who do read 10 to gain a month of reading proficiency.
The reason that I say that is because we have the budget from last year on the team program,
the adult program reading and the children's program reading summer reading program.
And we started off in July, saved for the children's with $1,500.
And by the end of March, we had $188.52.
And that's going to be cut further.
I know that we use our book budget to purchase janitorial supplies.
And we're constantly, you know, I will say Kelly is a strong go get her.
She's extremely thrifty.
She has gone to conventions.
And there was a vendor that she approached at one of the conventions.
And she said, we are not going to renew our contract with you.
We cannot afford this in the next year.
And at vendor said, I will cut it.
And I want to say it was 6,000 down to like 3,000 or 4,000.
6,900 to 2,400.
Because she attends the conventions because she continues the relationships.
And because she is constantly double checking on the prices.
She is constantly coming to us saying, I'm finding ways for us to cut this budget.
And we're going to do this.
And I do want to say every single member of that staff at the library is phenomenal.
They have amazing hearts. They give so much of themselves.
And they are extremely qualified and the work that they are doing.
And I want to applaud the city for raising their pay.
I, you know, with the cost of living, everything's going up.
And I think that was a great move.
However, when we're cutting the budget,
we also need to consider the training cost.
And is there money in the budget for them to have
continuing education units to, when they're going
to these conventions, when they're taking the classes
to keep maintaining and building on what we have here
in the community.
Finally, because I don't know how much time I have left,
I just, again, want to say, this city library,
our county library that benefits the entire county.
They are doing so much to improve the lives of the families
here.
The summer reading program, imagination,
library, constantly working.
They've even put in together a team program.
When we talk about what do we do with these kids,
and how do they not get in trouble and cost problems,
you know, for the city, the library is giving them an outlet.
And I just feel like we should invest in that.
And thank you very much for your time.
And thank you, good.
Thank you.
Oh, this is getting ready to be a double whammy.
I don't know if the time was coming yet.
I was going to add it to you.
Oh, OK.
Well, my name's Berkeley Oberie.
I'm her son.
And I just also wanted to come up here to talk a little bit about the library
budget.
The library has been a great asset.
And this community, it's definitely been a great asset for me.
Having access to all those books,
I probably myself, on being a voracious reader
and having the library there has been an incredible outlet
to lead to learn to expand my horizons.
And one thing I did want to mention is that the library has so many
outstanding, wholesome programs that benefit the community outside of just books
and new magazines and all those publications that they provide at no cost
to the members of the community.
I know for adults, if I remember correctly, they have helped with job search programs.
And there are so many great things that they do with the summer reading program, helping
make sure that young children in school, stay reading, even when school is out.
And I believe that the library could do so much more if there was just something else there
for them to use.
But here, these papers show and March, they were already running out in the children's program
and then the adult program and by February of this year they had already run through 90% of
their budget for pain expenses.
And it is just so hard for them to continue providing these outstanding resources for
community when there's just always that danger of being out and over budget.
And that's definitely a major issue that they face.
And then there's also some maintenance issues, some janitorial issues, there's issues with
the windows, there's issues with the elevator, that's unfortunately spend a lot of time
with trouble just getting up to the second floor because the elevators had issues working.
I recall they've also had issues with birds getting in through the roof.
There's just been a lot of issues with maintenance that they haven't been able to pursue.
And unfortunately, these issues all start to draw from the book budget because there's just
nowhere else for them to find from it's a major issue and I just came up here to ask for
consideration of these issues and how it hinders what otherwise such a great potential and
a great asset for the community.
Thank you.
Anyone else?
Public hearing for the budget?
There's no more comments.
We'll close the public hearing on the budget and we'll go to three public hearing, but let's
go to a personal period.
So I think the two we had already went, right?
Yes.
Okay.
Four claims list.
Most you approve?
Second.
Hi.
So full.
Jones.
Hi.
Hitton.
No.
Parker.
Hi.
Five.
Claims for an ideal concrete.
Motion approved.
Second.
So full.
Hi.
He said.
Jones.
Hi.
Hitton.
Parker.
Hi.
Six.
Minutes from the May 6, 2024.
Regular meeting.
Motion.
Sorry.
He said.
Hi.
37 meetings in each meeting.
I don't know what you'll get in this one.
I'll come down.
And then you're long enough.
I can't.
Seven.
Budget.
Twenty four nineteen transfer.
You miss you.
You a budget to.
Grants and donations along with the actual fund transfers from previous fiscal years.
From general fund.
Grants and donations on to the MSUA grant.
Relations fund.
Motion approved.
Second.
He said.
Hi.
Jones.
Parker.
Back.
Eight.
Fiscal Year 2425.
Municipal budget.
Message.
In Resolution.
Regarding.
The City of Miami.
Public.
department needed to transfer money to the water department. Well, that's all in fund $510 and
MSU A fund. The city manager have consigned that form on his own. Now, if the general fund needed money
at MSU A fund $510 needed to move money to 01, which is a general fund, then that would be the
amendment that the council would have. Is there a cap on that amount? No. There's a cap. There
is a little bit similar how much money can be transferred out of the MSU A, or not an MSU A purpose
and it's paying to is in the budget message, which is a pretty little book that has the
city manager's message and then some statistics. And then at the back of that it has a certificate
certification for the rainy day fund.
that is also white ordinance, and it sets how much the ring they find will be at the end of next year, so it's 630-25.
So those are the two things, the resolution and the certification.
If I could say a couple of things, I want to thank staff.
We all got together and worked on this.
A lot of human beings said, hey, this is the first time we've really got together and got to see how the budget was made.
You know, we had to make some hard decisions.
So the first question I asked in that meeting was, do we want to do raises for employees?
Or do we want to use that money elsewhere?
And the decision was, let's do raises for employees.
And then the second thing was, we had to go through and cut some stuff.
I mean, HD cut a police car.
I know there's a budget.
I know there's streets cut a couple of things out of their budget.
I can quit my lives.
I know parks cut a couple of things.
I'm just, you know, we kind of went through the list and everybody just like, hey, I cut this.
If you cut that, you know, I'm so we worked very hard.
I'm also willing to, you know, she'd awesome on her budget message.
So thank you very much, Melinda, and I know Jill too.
So thank you guys very much for the very hard on this.
We want to show the message that, you know, I mean, things cost more.
Just like when you go to the grocery store, they cost more.
But what we, you know, we're trying to do less with more.
So I mean, you know, this next year, I think we'd be going to do some bench marking on where we compare to other cities.
Obviously, we need to look at raising some of our, our fees and revenues to increase revenues to pay for stuff.
You know, GRD is going up opposite our tipping fees of one up.
I'm just some things like that.
So I'm excited to, I mean, the budget staff really got together and made it work.
I do have a question, Tyler, like in regards to the library specifically.
We're technically the only public library within the county correct.
Is there, is that's my understanding, Kayla?
Are we really, correct?
That's public.
So, is there any funding coming in from the county in that regard?
I was an opportunity to, to reach out to the other communities, man, the county and the commissioners.
I can't see if there's any funding in there.
Also along the same box, say sales tax revenues run higher than normal or making more than what we thought we were going to.
Right.
With these amendments, you can shift some of that light around, so if the library needs something or HD needs something, whatever you can, you have the ability to shift that around with the average.
We can do a bunch of amendments.
So, so we may be able to help.
If we're making more, we can do more.
I'm confident that we can do that.
Jones, E-Ceph, Kippen,
the whole parker.
Hi.
Not in contract minimum number one, for the annual six month,
as the aggregate rock supply, C-2039, with Kip Stone.
This is the same one, we're going to talk about it earlier.
Motion no further.
Thank you.
Hi.
E-Ceph.
Jones.
Hi.
Didn't it come to the parker?
It's like, they job we all over again.
To the contract with Concrete Sand's Apply, C-2033,
that's 60 with MuscoBee Sand,
the digital bonds mission of all of our contract documents.
Motion to approve.
E-Ceph.
Pippen.
Jones.
Hi.
Don't go.
Parker.
Hello.
An on-call open-transition boring.
Labor for a borderline replacement, C-2040,
10th Fisk, year 2425.
With M&J, equipment services,
Collins construction, B-town construction, LLC,
broadhead, boring LLC,
and recommend, as recommended by staff,
approve contracts,
contingent upon this mission of all required.
Contract documents and authorized in terms of C-2033,
his does need to sign,
knows to proceed.
Motion to approve.
Second.
E-Ceph.
Hi.
Good morning.
Jones.
Hi.
Parker.
12.
Award-high voltage line clearance,
tree trimming, and tree removal services, C-2044-29.
For this career, 2425,
to pro tree management,
as recommended by staff,
approve the contract,
depending upon submission of all required contract.
Documents and authorized in terms of C-2033,
his does need to sign,
knows to proceed.
Motion to approve.
Second.
E-Ceph.
Hi.
Good morning.
Jones.
Hi.
Parker.
13.
Ordnance 24 or 2024-02.
The Mending Section 28-40-GR,
some Cherry Class and fees.
Two Article 3,
Custom Fees and Chapter 28.
Symmeteries were provided for
conflicting provisions to
banning all conflicting ordinances
in the State of Asia,
and GAR,
G-A-R,
cemetery, rate increase.
So,
informed me with the request of councillor
But I believe there is exactly what you ask us to do, as soon as the ordinance is identical to what you had the last time in front of you.
But in the introductory paragraph, we added an equation that the City Council will review the fee schedule prior to the beginning of the next.
So, in Mayor June, the cheer, you'll review, well, let me add the intent is to make this, this works for you.
We're going to make this applied to all of our theme schedules.
So, in Mayor June, you would review those.
If you want to have us do something to the contrary, you absolutely have to write to do that.
It's required by ordinance that you look at all of these fee schedules.
But if you don't do something to the contrary, then it will have the consumer pricing mix.
Increase or decrease, come July 1, based on your off-taking and the other.
Could you explain the severability piece to me?
That is a purely legalese thing, basically, is saying any part of the ordinance is declared illegal or any constitutional
that the remainder of the ordinance in effect, as long as it makes sense with whatever it is that's been made.
Thank you.
Thank you for taking this back and working on it.
I appreciate that.
There's an easy change in it.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Aye.
So, aye.
Goodman.
Aye.
14.
Other new business, many of what's the reasons that's posting this agenda.
15.
Staff of importance.
16.
Mayor, council, community, and announcements.
I'd just like to say a special thanks to our crews who were out in the weather.
Just passed a couple of weeks.
It's been crazy and they've even gone so far as to go out and help other communities.
So, just extra special praise to go out to those guys and all the people that are behind that.
Thank you.
I'd like to say to kind of along the same lines of Brian.
A lot of people don't know that, you know, of course, Memorial Day was here.
Kevin's crew is swamped around that time.
Trying to keep up the cemetery and everything else.
Tyler's crew is electric crew.
I know everybody joined in and tried to help make it and get it cleaned up and looking good.
And I know that we even had some bad help with the baseball fields and help get them ready.
One of our firefighters.
Kate Whitton was down in the morning.
The baseball fields are getting ready.
So, I love the fact that the whole community is chippin' in.
And it's not about us.
It's about the kids and the communities.
So I appreciate that.
I appreciate our line career going to Clarence More,
helping me with the tornado.
I know the city manager there said he knew we sent a great crew
of guys and he put him in his toughest areas
and they got the job done.
So I think we hear that every time we send him out.
So we got a really good group of people.
So 17 city managers communications.
I have just a few.
The library wanted me to announce that there's
some reading program has officially kicked off as a June 1st.
And it's open all ages.
And they've also invited the council,
and the council members, they want to come down and participate.
I know utility screens are going to go down there
and read the street department's going to go read.
So they enjoy that.
I'm also, and I'll see what we're doing there.
Use on stage performances, June 13th, and 14th,
at 7pm and June 15th at 2pm.
So that'll be good.
And the last thing is we, and I'm kind of excited about this.
We received and episode of 10 in L.I.
We submitted for the initial, there's a big long acronym for it.
But project application for the city of Miami,
for a public safety center.
So we worked on getting some stuff together for this.
So we have been approved and your organization is here
by invited to complete it and submit a full project application.
So we made it through the first round.
So this would be a really cool public safety center
that would have placed in fire.
And then we'd have a satellite facility out in the southwest part
of Miami.
So we had a good meeting on that today.
The second round, I don't know if we'll make it farther,
but I mean, it's a new job by everybody involved.
Yeah, I'm excited about that.
So city manager, search, keep it on a take.
Yes, it'll go ahead, it's any.
I'm going to go with today.
And so we come here within the next couple of the group
that we get good games.
Is that good for everybody to do it at the next house?
May they want to have a special in between?
Mm-hmm.
Thanks, thanks.
OK.
18 adjournment.
Motion?
Sir?
Yes.
Aye.